<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Monica Spisar</title>
        <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Monica Spisar</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 13:08:18 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://monicaspisar.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Learning Rust</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/learn-rust/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 13:08:18 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/learn-rust/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[One of my 2024 batch goals at Recurse is to learn Rust.
How? work through three introductory Rust resources The Rust Book Rustlings Yet Another Rust Resource) implement a small project in Rust Public repos with solutions msyvr/rusty msyvr/rustlings msyvr/yarry Learning notes ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Recurse Center</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/recurse/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 11:00:17 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/recurse/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[&ldquo;The retreat where curious programmers recharge and grow&rdquo; I first joined the Recurse community in the fall of 2021, then returned for a second batch in the summer of 2024.
Recurse brands itself as the equivalent of a writers&rsquo; retreat - but for software engineers. Recursers work at the edge of their abilities to become dramatically better programmers during their batch, then never-graduate and join the 2000+ alumni community.
What do Recurses do during their batches?]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>ARENA: AI alignment</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/arena/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 22:42:57 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/arena/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ARENA @ RC 2024 During my second batch at RC, I joined a study group to cover the materials from Callum McDougall&rsquo;s Alignment Research Engineer Accelerator aka ARENA program which is normally delivered by LISI: the London Initiative for Safe AI.
notes coming soon! in the meanwhile, some of the resources I used&hellip; Recommended reading ImageNet Classification with Deep Convolutional Neural Networks
Generative Adversarial Nets
Attention is All You Need]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>README</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/readme/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 22:38:25 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/readme/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Welcome to a new version of my site.
In the past, I&rsquo;ve used a few other platforms for (sporadically) posting my writing (see Medium and Substack Posts). I&rsquo;m hoping that collecting everything in one place will lower the friction of posting, particularly small notes and reference links (see Etc). In the Recurse spirit, here&rsquo;s my small contribution to learning generously.
Site build Framework: Hugo Theme: LoveIt theme Custom CSS: /_override.scss Combo based on Régis&rsquo; excellent chronicle of his journey from software engineer to machine learning engineer, with detailed guidance for setting up a Hugo/LoveIt site here.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Machine learning fundamentals</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/machine-learning-fundamentals/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 16:37:09 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/machine-learning-fundamentals/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Resources Backprop The paper that started it all: Letters to Nature: Learning representation by back-propagating errors (pdf)
Batch norm How does batch normalization help optimization? (pdf)
Model evaluation Evaluating Large Language Models Trained on Code
Fine tuning models: domain-adaptive pre-training Continual Pre-training of Language Models
Synthetic data Machine Learning for Synthetic Data Generation: A Review
Cosmopedia: how to create large-scale synthetic data for pre-training Large Language Models
Practice projects Karpathy: Micrograd karpathy/micrograd: A tiny scalar-valued autograd engine and a neural net library on top of it with PyTorch-like API (github)]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Raytracer</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/raytracer/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 22:43:54 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/raytracer/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[During my first Recurse Center retreat in the fall of 2021, I worked on code craftsmanship and experimented with a variety of software engineering concepts. One tangent led me to writing a ray tracing engine.
GPUs rule In the course of exploring photorealistic image generation for movies and games, I discovered that the practical execution of algorithms which simulate realistic (physics-based) illumination is made possible by phenomenal advances in dedicated hardware, supported by machine learning.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Medium and Substack (old) posts</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/medium-and-substack-posts/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 19:02:34 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/medium-and-substack-posts/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In addition to research publications, I have a small collection of prior publicly-shared works on Medium and Substack. A few posts from each:
Medium: msyvr Picture perfect: AI + medical imaging
&ldquo;Leave me in peace, Wizard.&rdquo;: Notes on James Mickens&rsquo; talk at USENIX Security &lsquo;18
Seeing withing: Magical imaging
Substack: gaming aging Mainstreaming longevity: scaling biohacking
Hedging bets on healthier aging]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Mickens Usenix 2018</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/mickens-usenix-2018/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 18:56:48 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/mickens-usenix-2018/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[James Mickens on the value of skepticism Notes from James Mickens&rsquo; talk at USENIX Security &lsquo;18.
If you haven&rsquo;t seen James&rsquo; talk and have an hour to view his actual keynote, please do yourself a favor and just go see his talk. It&rsquo;s entertaining, educational, and thought provoking. Absolutely not to be missed - the most fun you&rsquo;ll have while thinking about cybersecurity, machine learning, and computing more generally. Case in point, a fun still from his talk…]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Picture Perfect: AI &#43; Medical Imaging</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/picture-perfect/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 18:03:52 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/picture-perfect/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Picture perfect: AI + medical imaging Caveat emptor! Written in November 2017. Progress in AI is astonishingly rapid: this is inevitably out of date.
Radiology&rsquo;s inevitable evolution Artificial intelligence (AI) in medical imaging is a controversial topic - up for debate are questions regarding its implementation (from both technical and regulatory standpoints), ultimate potential (presuming it has the theoretical potential to do better, will it do better in practice, and how might it alter clinical processes?]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Seeing Within</title>
    <link>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/seeing-within/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 19:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Monica Spisar</author>
    <guid>https://monicaspisar.com/posts/seeing-within/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Seeing within: Magical imaging Much of the complexity of the human body is shrouded in mystery. But we know a lot more than we used to about its structure and function. Structure (anatomy), in particular, has been mapped out in meticulous detail. In the distant past, building up static anatomical maps relied on information from dissections. Yeah, gross. Also, pretty much useless to a live person needing guidance for treatment of injury or disease, or for monitoring a chronic condition.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
